<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0"><channel><title>BoongoTV</title><link>https://kodi.tv</link><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.kodi.tv/xbmc" /><description>ElectricalForce is a free media player that is designed to look great on your big screen TV but is just as at home on a small screen.</description><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 19:19:30 PDT</lastBuildDate><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.kodi.tv/xbmc" /><feedburner:info uri="xbmc" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item><title>Switching Translations to Weblate</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/yEmrJOe-ny4/</link><category>Developer</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Team Kodi</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 03:44:04 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/switching-translations-to-weblate/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Photo by Edurne Chopeitia on Unsplash" alt="Photo by Edurne Chopeitia on Unsplash" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/dictionary-image-photo-by-edurne-chopeitia-on-unsplash.jpg" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>The moment is here to move to an even more optimal translation service for our application. Ultimately we have chosen Weblate, and its service will be hosted at <a href="https://kodi.weblate.cloud/">https://kodi.weblate.cloud/</a>.</p>
<p>This is done to optimize our workflow and to allow easy inclusion of all add-ons in the official Kodi add-on repository.</p>
<p>The transition has taken its time during at least the last year, so if you have made any requests at Transifex for new languages or team additions in that period, we're sorry we couldn't implement them.</p>
<p>All current translations have been transferred to Weblate, and we would like to thank you for all your efforts in making Kodi the multi-lingual success it is. We hope you will join us in our revived efforts to make Kodi accessible to even more languages using Weblate.</p>
<p>For now, our most current resources at Transifex are locked, meaning translators will no longer have access. The final switch over to Weblate is planned for July the 14th, 2021. We hope to see you all there.</p>
<p>Please sign up at Weblate here:</p>
<p><a href="https://kodi.weblate.cloud/accounts/register/">https://kodi.weblate.cloud/accounts/register/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://kodi.weblate.cloud/accounts/register/"></a>You can visit this forum post to let us know which language team you would like access to (and if you are a coordinator for that language): <a href="https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=363132">https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=363132</a></p>
<p>We encourage all add-on developers with add-ons in the official Kodi add-on repository to submit their add-ons for translation: <a href="https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=363251&#x26;pid=3045468#pid3045468">https://forum.kodi.tv/showthread.php?tid=363251&#x26;pid=3045468#pid3045468</a></p>
<p>Best regards,</p>
<p>The Kodi Translations Team</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/yEmrJOe-ny4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>The moment is here to move to an even more optimal translation service for our application. Ultimately we have chosen Weblate, and its…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/switching-translations-to-weblate/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>The Votes Have Been Counted and Verified...</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/TKUiSpMManA/</link><category>Community</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:42:48 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/the-votes-have-been-counted-and-verified/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Credit: Photo by Emily Morter on Unsplash" alt="Credit: Photo by Emily Morter on Unsplash" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/emily-morter-8xaa0f9yqne-unsplash.jpg" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>Many of you will probably be aware that, since the dawn of time, each version of Kodi takes a vaguely sci-fi/fantasy/movie-themed name, in alphabetical order (<em>Ed: no, don't ask what happens after we get to Z</em>). This has become common practice throughout the IT industry - look at iOS, Android, Ubuntu, Intel chips, and similar: it provides a useful and friendly way to refer to a release without getting tied up in numbers and decimal points.</p>
<p>Anyway, over the past 13 years or so we've chewed through Atlantis, Babylon, Camelot, Dharma, Eden, Frodo, Gotham, Helix, Isengard, Jarvis, Krypton, Leia and Matrix ... and, as we branch the code for the next release, it's time to bestow a name on our next version.</p>
<p>We ran a thread on the forum (thank you to everyone for their suggestions), filtered them for repetition, our ability to remember how to type them, and general scandal, and then put the top community-suggested names to a Team vote.</p>
<p>While we've previously had very specific names, this one is perhaps a little broader in its reference.</p>
<p>So, is it...</p>
<ul>
<li>A series designator for replicants?</li>
<li>An extra-dimensional realm that exists outside of space and time, visited by both Kirk and Picard?</li>
<li>A post-cyberpunk trilogy by Ramez Naam?</li>
<li>A dungeon in World of Warcraft?</li>
<li>The heart of every protoss settlement in StarCraft?</li>
<li>All of the above, and perhaps more?</li>
</ul>
<p>Ladies, gentlemen, non-binary, non-human, and inorganic lifeforms... I give you ...</p>
<h3>Kodi 20 "Nexus"</h3>
<p><em>&#x3C; muted fanfare ></em></p>
<p>Don't get too excited about a new version dropping any time soon, as 19.x "Matrix" is still fresh out of the oven. However, you now know what's coming, and, if you're inclined, you can now follow development of this specific branch.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/TKUiSpMManA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Many of you will probably be aware that, since the dawn of time, each version of Kodi takes a vaguely sci-fi/fantasy/movie-themed name, in…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/the-votes-have-been-counted-and-verified/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi "Matrix" 19.1 Release</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/F104jV7WW7Q/</link><category>Release</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 12:35:04 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-matrix-19-1-release/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.1 "Matrix" Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.1 "Matrix" Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/19.1-splash.jpg" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that, no matter how much testing you do before a major release, you'll never find and squash anything like all the bugs until you get a proper, large-scale, mass test of the code. In other words, it's time for a bugfix release on the Kodi 19 "Matrix" series, as - thanks to your feedback - we've managed to fix a whole batch of issues over the past few weeks.</p>
<p>In no particular order, this version includes fixes for the following:</p>
<p>As a bug fix release, don't bother going to look for new features; while there are some, that's not the main purpose of this version. Full details are on <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0-Matrix...v19.1-Matrix">GitHub</a>, but here's the short form...</p>
<p><strong>Video</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: HDR metadata is now detected in VP9 profile 2 streams and can be used on platforms that support HDR passthrough or tone mapped when playing this kind of videos.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Discs</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: playback of optical DVDs in Linux</li>
<li>Fixed: BD-J Blu-ray chapter skipping via remotes/keyboard</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>PVR</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: context menu not accessible in PVR Guide window when using very basic remote to control Kodi</li>
<li>Fixed: client channel name and number not persisted when changed</li>
<li>Fixed: play count and resume position of recordings lost after Kodi restart</li>
<li>Fixed: crash while browsing the EPG when MySQL is used as EPG database</li>
<li>Fixed: next recording on ... label time is not localized in Estuary Timer/Timer rules window</li>
<li>Fixed: channel manager does not rename backend channel</li>
<li>Fixed: playing archived programme not selected when opening the Guide window</li>
<li>Fixed: GUI not updated on removal/insert/hide/unhide of channel groups</li>
<li>Updated: improved look of PVR windows in Estuary</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Music Library</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: issue with music from cuesheets where only the first track was being added to the library on rescanning, with the rest being deleted</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JSON-RPC</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: PVR - Reintroduced broadcast properties 'hastimer', 'hastimerrule', 'hasrecording', 'recording'</li>
<li>Fixed: PVR - Reintroduced channel property 'isrecording'</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Subtitles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: detection of system fonts (directwrite) on windows for ASS subtitles</li>
<li>Fixed: detection of user fonts (in userdata/fonts) for ASS subtitles</li>
<li>Fixed: rendering of semi-transparent ASS subtitles on Wayland</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>GUI/Interface</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: media flagging for DVD/BluRay</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Web Interface</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated: Chorus2 based on community contributions</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Filesystem</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated: enable filecaching by default for network filesystems</li>
<li>Updated: improve filecache error handling</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Network</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Updated: improved reliability for HTTP and NFS network filesystems</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Windows specifics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added: support for WS-Discovery protocol that enables locating SMB servers and browsing shared folders using SMBv3.</li>
<li>Added: debug Info OSD Video. Extends current Debug Info Player (Ctrl+Shift+O) with new video-only info (Alt+O)</li>
<li>Fixed: with some unusual streams, incorrect HDR metadata could be passed (HDR10 passthrough).</li>
<li>Fixed: green screen on systems with old HW (DX feature level 9.1) playing 10-bit videos.</li>
<li>Fixed: black screen with Software render method and with DXVA2 hardware acceleration disabled.</li>
<li>Fixed: green screen when playing the menu of some DVDs (MPEG2 SD only).</li>
<li>Fixed: credentials being requested for anonymous SMB shares</li>
<li>Updated: VC runtimes included in the installer to add compatibility with VS2019 and VS2017 at the same time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Android specifics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed: SMB shares mounted on system level not visible in Kodi</li>
<li>Fixed: SMB shares labelled with cryptic numbers (UUID) instead of actual disk name</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xbox specifics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This version also brings 19.1 to the Xbox - while 19.0 has been in the Microsoft Store since launch, this was Windows-only while we found a way to adequately test the new release on Xbox. We've fixed that now, so Xbox users will automatically upgrade from 18.9 to 19.1 if you've got auto-update enabled. It's worth mentioning that there's a known memory limitation - present in 18.x as well - that causes Xbox application crashes with 4k content, so please be aware.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>*EDIT</strong> Ah, so close. Sadly, this isn't going to happen - there's a new issue that's bubbled up on Xbox that means you can't download any addons, which is a touch... inconvenient. As such, we've had to pull Xbox 19.1 - sorry, folks. Let's see if we can resolve that for 19.2...*</p>
<p><br>
Thanks to everyone who has helped by reporting, isolating or fixing issues.</p>
<p>As usual, there really should be no problems in installing this straight over the top of your existing Kodi version - indeed, this will happen automatically on many platforms - but, if you've any doubts, back up your userdata beforehand. Similarly, this is a minor version bump, so there's no change to database versions or anything else that's likely to break things.</p>
<p>If you're interested, you can read the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Matrix+19.1%22+label%3A%22v19+Matrix%22+">here</a>. If you want to read back on the full history of v19 itself, or of previous versions, you can find the corresponding articles in the relevant <a href="https://kodi.tv/tags/release-announcements">blog posts</a>.</p>
<p>Application deployment on different platforms (notably, Google Play and the Microsoft Store) can vary considerably due to circumstances outside of our control, so just be patient, and the update will inevitably find its way through.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/F104jV7WW7Q" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>It is a truth universally acknowledged that, no matter how much testing you do before a major release, you'll never find and squash anything…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-matrix-19-1-release/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>"Kodi Broke My Addons!"</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/iKShsF-ptos/</link><category>Community</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Team Kodi</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 03:35:45 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-broke-my-addons/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Image of Python code, credit: Johnson Martin from Pixabay" alt="Image of Python code, credit: Johnson Martin from Pixabay" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/python_code-johnson_martin_pixabay.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>Since we released 19.0 "Matrix", we've been hearing a lot of noise about how people's addons have stopped working, and why we're all Really Bad People for doing this. We thought it would be worth helping people understand what's happening here - mostly, because our fingers are getting tired from trying to explain, and it'll save an awful lot of typing in the forum, or on Facebook, or wherever.</p>
<p>Please remember, first of all, that Kodi itself does <strong>not</strong> automatically update. We might tell you that a new version is available, sure, but we never force a new version onto you: that's entirely a product of your chosen operating system and configuration. It's probably enabled by default; it may be something you have to trigger; it may be a completely manual process - but it's not under our control. We're genuinely not "forcing a new release onto you", but we equally can do nothing to stop an automatic update if you have it enabled.</p>
<h3>From Ancient History ...</h3>
<p>So, where did this all come from.</p>
<p>Kodi's addons traditionally ran in Python 2, which was first released in <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20091214142515/http://www.amk.ca/python/2.0">October 2000</a>. Some years after release - in the distant days of 2008, when Katy Perry and Kings of Leon were the new kids in town, and The Dark Knight and Indiana Jones were still huge in the cinema - it was announced that Python 2 was scheduled to go end-of-life in 2015. Before they got there, though, the Python team realised that people were slow in making the switch, and decided to extend this EOL date further to 1st January 2020. You can read all about that <a href="https://www.python.org/doc/sunset-python-2/">here</a>.</p>
<p>So, aware that the clock was ticking loudly - and that we were already behind the curve - we announced in January 2018 that we'd drop Python 2 support from Kodi <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/attention-addon-developers-migration-python-3">in version 19</a>. Given that we were on 17.x "Krypton" at the time, and we hadn't made any breaking changes to Python since shifting to Python 2 in 2013, this seemed fair. Remember, as well, that 18 "Leia" didn't see the light of day as a final release until January 2019, so Kodi 19 wasn't exactly going to leap out suddenly at anyone - so we felt that this was adequate notice for developers and users to prepare for the change. This is, after all, not just our issue: the whole software industry had to make this switch, so you'll have seen, for example, Canonical making the switch to pure Python 3 on Ubuntu with their <a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/Python">18.04 release</a>.</p>
<p>Python 3 builds of 18.x "Leia" were available, and the code was in the Python 3 feature branch - but this was merged in <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/commit/c0968c9b83fa82358654a8d8fc392806302c6a6f">October 2019</a>, so any build after that date would have included it. More broadly, developer builds of Kodi 19 became available in <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-python-3-goes-live">November 2019</a>, with Alpha builds following along in August of last year. That means, nearly two years after saying we were making the switch, the first test builds of a pure Python 3 Kodi became available - and we've then finally switched over our release code just over a year later. That's three years after the initial announcement.</p>
<h3>... to Today</h3>
<p>And yet... and yet... the move seems to have taken people by surprise. Operating systems have dropped support for Python 2; it's a huge security risk, as it (and its libraries) are unmaintained; you shouldn't be using it unless you really, really have to. And yet...</p>
<p>To really rub salt into the wound, it's not really <strong>our</strong> addons that are causing grief. Some justifiable complaints are around skins, and we understand that: if you have a favourite skin that isn't compatible with the new release, or has fallen out of fashion, then it's a jolt to have to change - but the skin developers are entitled to maintain or not maintain their work, that's entirely up to them. It's not just skins, though: there are very many third-party addons out there that are having problems, and that's where we're getting a lot of flak.</p>
<p>It's arguable that you really shouldn't be using these if they require you to use an unmaintained platform, but that's your choice. We've genuinely done our best, and we simply have no influence or control over these addons, however useful they may be, whatever you use them for. There is a simple reality that major version bumps nearly always leave some platform or component behind, plus there's a truth that addons often simply wither and die - if the author doesn't want to maintain them, eventually, they rot.</p>
<h3>Options, Options, Options</h3>
<p>So, whinge over. What can you do if you're caught in this trap.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Well, if you really want to, you can stick on Python 2 with whatever addons you choose - stay on 18.x "Leia" and never update your operating system, as a future patch or wholesale upgrade is likely to remove Python 2.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you're on Android and have had a forced update, be aware that "auto update" is enabled by default on applications from the Play Store. Switch this off, and you'll stick with whatever version you have installed. You <em>may</em> be able to do this on a per-application basis as well, but that varies by Android platform.</li>
<li>If you're on Linux, be careful of <em>apt update</em> or similar, as repositories are likely to automatically shift you to the next release (our PPA definitely will). Likewise, an OS update is likely to pick up different versions of all pre-installed applications, including Kodi, if it's from a distro-maintained repository.</li>
<li>If you're on a JeOS "bundled" platform, be sure to switch off auto-update in <em>Settings</em> - or keep a beady eye on it, anyway. LibreELEC is probably the most common platform here, and that has no auto-update between major versions ("channels") anyway, but other platforms exist, or you may have updated manually.</li>
<li>Windows, it depends on how you installed it. If you've downloaded from our web site, simply don't upgrade it; if you're using the UWP version from the Windows Store, then you'll need to disable "Update apps automatically" for all applications.</li>
<li>Apple devices are typically user-installed (e.g. sideloaded), so just don't install something new. The exception is if you're using a repo on a jailbroken device (e.g. Cydia) - in which case, you're in the same boat as Linux repo users.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>If you've already updated, you can normally go back. This can be tricky on some platforms (e.g. Android), where you'll need to be careful to uninstall the application <em>but not the data</em>, and then re-install the app alone. Similarly, on a JeOS distro, you're likely to have to export your library and addon settings where you can, re-install, and then re-import everything. To explain for every platform is outside of the scope of this blog post, so perhaps turn to the forum for help here.</li>
<li>Be aware that <em>every</em> major version bump in Kodi upgrades your database. Downgrading should immediately revert to the previous version in whatever state it was (e.g. watched status) when you upgraded, but there are implications if you use a shared database across multiple client versions.</li>
<li>You can lobby your addon authors to get their collective fingers out and make the shift to Python 3 - as said above, this is hardly new news to anyone. Other than addons we write and provide, we have absolutely no control or influence over whether they get ported to Python 3, or whether they stay on 2 (and thus you can't go past Kodi 18 "Leia").</li>
</ul>
<p>We're not currently planning any future changes of this scale, so the next couple of versions are likely to be a far easier ride. However, with those upcoming releases, just like this one, you have choices, and you're always in control of your own devices - so, please, don't have a go at us or leave us lousy reviews when we've really tried our best here, and yet something well outside of our control (your platform, your settings, third-party addons, maybe even third-party repositories) has broken something.</p>
<p><code>&#x3C;/grump></code></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/iKShsF-ptos" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Since we released 19.0 "Matrix", we've been hearing a lot of noise about how people's addons have stopped working, and why we're all Really…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-broke-my-addons/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.0 "Matrix" - Release</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/ytntajutQp4/</link><category>Release</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:49:22 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-0-matrix-release/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19 Matrix splash screen" alt="Kodi 19 Matrix splash screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/kodi_splash_v19.0_matrix_final_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>... yes, it's here! After several iterations of alpha, beta and RC, Team Kodi is pleased to announce that Kodi 19.0 "Matrix" has just been formally released on all supported platforms. Dare you take the red pill, and find out how deep the rabbit-hole goes?</p>
<p>By the numbers, then, this version is the product of:</p>
<ul>
<li>Nearly 50 individual open source developers contributed code</li>
<li>About 5,000 commits in over 1,500 pull requests since the first release of 18.x "Leia"</li>
<li>Over 5,500 changed files, with some 600,000 lines of code added, changed or removed</li>
<li>Countless hours of dedicated free time conceiving, designing, developing and testing (including all the infrastructure you see around them, including this web site)</li>
<li>... and, of course,very little travelling, obviously - that's not good at the moment!</li>
</ul>
<p>The broad list of new features is below, but - before we get to that - I'd just like to take a moment to say "thank you" to the huge amounts of work put in by the broadest team behind this release. Whether you submitted a few lines of code or a major new feature; whether you worked on video, audio, gaming, or a skin; whether you tested in pre-release and helped identify a problem, debugged an issue or updated a translation; whether you fixed some documentation, looked after the various systems that keep kodi.tv running, or helped to moderate the forum - thank you, one and all. Kodi is a community, and, without all of you, we would all lose something.</p>
<p>So, onward - what have we got. If you've been following the release cycle, you'll have seen these already, but for people who only take final releases... hold on, it's a long list!</p>
<h5><strong>Kodi 19 "Matrix" Features</strong></h5>
<p><strong>Playback</strong></p>
<p>For audio and music lovers, there are significant improvements across the board to metadata handling: library improvements, new tags, new displays, improvements to how Kodi handles release dates, album durations, multi-disc sets, and more. There's a new, Matrix-inspired visualisation, there are improvements to display when fetching files from a web server, and several changes to how audio decoder addons can pass information through to the Kodi player.</p>
<p>For video, most of the changes are more technical, and may depend on your hardware: AV1 software decoding, HLG HDR and static HDR10 playback on Windows 10, static HDR10 and dynamic Dolby Vision HDR support on Android, and more OpenGL bicubic scalers.</p>
<p>For those who combine the two, and have libraries of music videos, you get some goodies as well: database and metadata display improvements mean that Kodi will now fetch and display related album and artist information from the music library, where appropriate. There are also new features around grouping videos by artist (not just album), support for .NFO files that list all performers instead of just the main artist, plus better search links to return related albums and videos by the same director director.</p>
<p>And, finally, if your definition of "play" is more game-related, we've implemented integer scaling to improve the viewing quality of Pixel Art games across the board, while iOS get support for Xbox, PlayStation and other supported Bluetooth game controllers.</p>
<p><strong>Skin/Look-and-Feel</strong></p>
<p>For many people, the interface is Kodi - it's how you find your way around, it's how you interact with the application and your media. As such, it's always getting some attention, and this release is no different: screen redesign, especially for music; new metadata displays; changes to playlist views; a new "now playing" view; artwork and image file improvements; both new and updated GUI controls. Some changes may be subtle, but all are designed to improve your experience.</p>
<p><strong>Subtitles</strong></p>
<p>An often-overlooked feature, but immensely useful to so many people, subtitles get some attention in this release: timestamp overlays get fixed, plus you can now select a dark grey colour and set an opacity for the captions (particularly useful in HDR - protect your eyes, kids, you'll miss them when they're gone).</p>
<p><strong>Addons and Scrapers</strong></p>
<p>Python comes in for some major changes in Kodi 19. Because the old Python 2.7 has gone out of support, we've finally made the wholesale move to <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-python-3-goes-live">Python 3</a> and ported our addons across. Much of the community has come with us, so, hopefully, your favourite addons will still function, but we're at the mercy of third-party contributors to update their work.</p>
<p>Kodi 19 replaces the old XML metadata scrapers with new default Python for movies and TV shows; there are also new Python scrapers for music, Generic Album Scraper and Generic Artist Scraper. Binary addons in general get improvements to system documentation, cleaned up settings dialogs, and better help text.</p>
<p><strong>PVR and Live Television</strong></p>
<p>Another significant part of Kodi that's had a lot of attention in this release. Most new features here revolve around usability: PVR reminders, home screen widgets, group/channel manager enhancements, navigation and dialog controls, context menus, New/Live/Finale/Premiere tags, channel numbering and sorting, performance improvements, API improvements.</p>
<p><strong>Security</strong></p>
<p>There are a few new security features implemented now in Kodi, to help keep you safe from intentional or unintentional problems. Kodi will now enforce the origin of installed addons and their dependencies, which prevents third-party repositories from overwriting code of unrelated add-ons; broken or deprecated add-ons are now highlighted in the add-on list, so you have to actively agree to activate one; the binary addon system now has higher security around data exchange between Kodi and an addons. In addition, we've added a default requirement to password-protect Kodi's web interface, plus give better information around the security implications of enabling external interfaces if you do choose to enable them.</p>
<p><strong>Platform Specifics</strong></p>
<p>As a cross-platform application, we try our very best to keep all platforms feature equivalent where we can. However, there are inevitably platform differences, and we also have to make room by dropping old platforms as technology moves on.</p>
<p>The big platform change with this release is new support for tvOS, but this means waving goodbye to <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-welcomes-tvos-says-goodbye-ios-32bit">iOS 32-bit</a>. Beyond that, there are specific tweaks such as specific TopShelf support and fixes on AppleTV, better logging and notch support on iOS, and a move to a single Linux binary for multiple windowing systems (X11, Wayland, and GBM) versus the previous three. That last one will make a big difference to both users and package maintainers, since you'll no longer have to select a different binary based on the target environment.</p>
<p><strong>Behind the Scenes</strong></p>
<p>Probably too hidden for many users, but there are inevitably changes and improvements that you can't see, but might give more scope for new features later on: API changes to feed subtitle URIs to the player; multiple updates to various core modules; improvements to API calls and actions, and many more. They may not be important to you, but they took real work and I mention them for completeness.</p>
<h5><strong>Kodi V19 "Matrix" Gear</strong></h5>
<p>Why not show your support with a Kodi 19 "Matrix" <a href="https://teespring.com/kodi-matrix">shirt or hoodie</a>? Or maybe a <a href="https://teespring.com/kodi-matrix?pid=650">pillow</a> to lounge on while you enjoy your favourite media? As well as just making you look utterly, fabulously, unquestionably cool, all purchases will make a small donation to the Foundation, and help keep everything running the way we all like it. All are available in a series of achingly-fashionable colours.</p>
<p><a href="https://teespring.com/kodi-matrix"><img src="/images/blog/Matrix%20T-shirt.webp" alt="Kodi 19.x &#x22;Matrix&#x22; T-shirt"></a><a href="https://teespring.com/kodi-matrix?pid=650"><img src="/images/blog/Matrix%20Cushion.webp" alt="Kodi 19.x &#x22;Matrix&#x22; Cushion"></a></p>
<h5><strong>Changelog</strong></h5>
<p>For the terminally-curious, you can view the <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?page=1&#x26;q=label%3A%22v19+Matrix%22+is%3Aclosed">merged pull requests on GitHub</a>. If you want to read back on the full history of v19 itself, or of previous versions, you can find the corresponding articles in the relevant <a href="https://kodi.tv/tags/release-announcements">blog posts</a>.</p>
<h5><strong>Help Wanted!</strong></h5>
<p>If you experience any issues or find any remaining bugs, please post in the <a href="https://forum.kodi.tv/forumdisplay.php?fid=111">General Support</a> section of our forum. If you have fixes for issues please submit a pull request with your changes to our <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc">master branch on GitHub</a>. We also welcome users who want to help answer questions in the forum or write articles for the wiki.</p>
<h5><strong>Donate</strong></h5>
<p>To show support and appreciation for Kodi, please consider <a href="/donate">making a donation</a> or <a href="/store">purchasing merchandise</a> such as a T-shirt or Raspberry Pi case. Your donations help us operate, covering operating expenses, hardware and software licences for developers, and legal fees, as well as paying for team members to attend industry/FLOSS events and our annual conference.</p>
<h5><strong>Availability</strong></h5>
<p>Kodi 19.0 "Matrix" is being pushed to the usual channels right now, so should be with your devices shortly. The exception is the Windows Store build for Xbox: this will, unfortunately, be delayed, and may even be subject to a future point release. x64 and x86 builds are going ahead, however, and will appear once they get through the store certification and deployment processes.</p>
<p>And, on that note, please remember that deployment on different platforms - especially curated "app stores", as above - can vary wildly due to circumstances outside of our control. It may thus take a few more days to appear everywhere, so just hang on until it gets to you.</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/ytntajutQp4" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>... yes, it's here! After several iterations of alpha, beta and RC, Team Kodi is pleased to announce that Kodi 19.0 "Matrix" has just been…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-0-matrix-release/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Release Candidate</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/2RuFZfJGllQ/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 07:54:23 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-x-matrix-release-candidate/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 RC Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 RC Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/kodi_splash_v19.0_matrix_rc_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>And, off we go again. The dust settles on the festive season, so it's time for another pre-release to hit the streets... we're getting close to final release now, so we're moving out of Beta and into RC.</p>
<p>If you want to know the main features in this release series, please refer back to previous blog posts: this is an iteration of previous Beta releases, not a feature release, remember.</p>
<p>This is stable, reliable code, suitable for daily use. Please, then: install, test, and give us clear feedback on any remaining issues, either with the new features or perhaps with a regression in existing code. As this is a release candidate, we think it's basically ready to go, but let's aim to make sure.</p>
<p>You can get this release from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/releases/">here</a> or - if appropriate - our nightly PPA <a href="https://launchpad.net/~team-xbmc/+archive/ubuntu/xbmc-nightly">here</a>. If you're on Android, you can <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/org.xbmc.kodi">enrol</a> in our Beta programme and get updates directly from Google Play.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also see changes since the last release <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0b2-Matrix...19.0RC1-Matrix">here</a> or browse the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+is%3Aclosed+milestone%3A%22Matrix+19.0-RC1%22">here</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/2RuFZfJGllQ" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>And, off we go again. The dust settles on the festive season, so it's time for another pre-release to hit the streets... we're getting close…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19-x-matrix-release-candidate/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Refactoring of the Add-on Subsystem</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/rENAks71Gyk/</link><category>Developer</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Frank H.</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 16:52:00 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/refactoring-of-the-add-on-subsystem/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Rubik's Cube: Photo by Olav Ahrens Røtne on Unsplash" alt="Rubik's Cube: Photo by Olav Ahrens Røtne on Unsplash" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/olav-ahrens-rotne-jvBXiynINGE-unsplash.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>Hey everybody,</p>
<p>In June 2020 some suggestions on improvements to our add-on system were suggested by Matt Huisman and some minor changes were implemented. Who knew at the time but this turned into much more work both cleaning up the current add-on system and adding numerous new features. The main goal of this became to improve the add-on user experience and add security features in order to prevent add-ons and repositories from being misused by bad actors.</p>
<p>The main problems were founded in the initial design of the add-on system, which doesn't distinguish between official and third-party repositories. This allows a mixup of installing and updating add-ons based only on their version information, regardless of their origin.</p>
<p>In order to tackle these issues and make the add-on system more robust as a whole, the following cornerstone changes were implemented to the add-on subsystem:</p>
<ul>
<li>The official Kodi add-on repository and its origin - kodi.tv-mirrors - are now defined as such. This repository contains all add-ons approved by Team Kodi.</li>
<li>Proper update rule restrictions were set up, which means official versions will be preferred during update over non official. Additionally add-ons are now bound to their origin to stop cross-updating and mixing of official and third-party add-ons.</li>
<li>Add-ons now stick to their origin for automated updates - this means the end user still has the freedom to choose between official or third-party add-on, they'd like to use, but updates will no longer switch from official to third-party and vice versa based solely on the highest version number.</li>
<li>Add-ons that do not originate from a repository (e.g. zip- or manually installed) will no longer receive updates. I.e. they will be pinned (Add-ons from an official repo are an exception to this rule).</li>
<li>General improvement of pinning mechanisms. Add-ons downgraded to a lower version within their origin don't get auto updated until they're switched back to their latest version.</li>
<li>Improved migration process - add-ons marked as incompatible during migration can be auto updated on the next Kodi startup.</li>
</ul>
<p>The subsystem work allowed the following GUI changes to be implemented:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can now see the origin of add-ons and their pinning status (especially use in the All Repositories view).</li>
<li>You can see whether or not an add-on was (or will be) installed from a repo (and if that repo was official) in all views.</li>
<li>You can see if an add-on was installed from zip or is a system add-on in all views.</li>
<li>Many other UI consistency fixes around add-ons.</li>
</ul>
<p>Lastly there were many, so many long time bugs and inconsistencies that came to the surface while doing this work, and all these that we know about so far have been fixed. In the end, the user experience of the add-on system shouldn't change too much, but should be a more enjoyable overall.</p>
<p>Here are some of the things we would like to tackle in V20:</p>
<ul>
<li>Signing of add-ons: the ability to identify an author across multiple repos. This enables things like trusted beta repos etc. Call for volunteers on this one, we don’t have any in team experience on cross platform signing!</li>
<li>Sandboxing of binary add-ons: Prevent binary add-ons from crashing Kodi</li>
<li>Navigating add-ons: Better tagging, and searching of add-ons.</li>
</ul>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>phunkyfish &#x26; frank (howie)</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/rENAks71Gyk" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Hey everybody, In June 2020 some suggestions on improvements to our add-on system were suggested by Matt Huisman and some minor changes were…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/refactoring-of-the-add-on-subsystem/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi @Remote Chaos Experience (RC3)</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/6Ro7uJoqCu0/</link><category>Conferences</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">yol</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 16:52:25 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-remote-chaos-experience-rc3/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Heya fellow net dwellers,</p>
<p>Right now the <a href="https://rc3.world/">Remote Chaos Experience (RC3)</a> is already running at full steam as virtual replacement for the 37th Chaos Communication Congress (37C3) that was supposed to be held in Leipzig, Germany, at exactly this time.</p>
<p>While we did not register an official assembly, some Team Kodi members are roaming around the RC3 world and we will use the opportunity to hold a short <strong>"What's new" presentation</strong> plus Q&#x26;A session on the last day of the congress. The exact date and time is <strong>Wednesday, 30th December, 2 p.m. CET</strong>.</p>
<p>The event is over and the recording is available on <a href="https://youtu.be/5rG_BFA-U6o">YouTube</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/6Ro7uJoqCu0" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Heya fellow net dwellers, Right now the Remote Chaos Experience (RC3) is already running at full steam as virtual replacement for the 37th…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-remote-chaos-experience-rc3/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Beta 2</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/pMIDQ3Bf5pA/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 21:45:00 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-beta-2/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 Beta Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 Beta Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/kodi_splash_v19.0_matrix_beta_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>So, here we go again. Nothing earth-shattering, just a quick note to tell you that the second Beta of Kodi 19.x "Matrix" is now available for installation.</p>
<p>If you want to know the main features in this release series, please refer back to previous blog posts, especially the <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-beta-1">Beta 1 announcement</a>: this is entirely a bugfix release, so - as befits a second Beta - there are no new features over Beta 1.</p>
<p>By this stage, there should be no show-stopping bugs, and this release should be pretty reliable - just make sure you know how to roll back, just in case. Please: install, test, and give us clear feedback on any issues you uncover, either with the new features or perhaps with a regression in existing code. We can then work to resolve these before we go to full release.</p>
<p>You can get Beta 2 from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/releases/">here</a>, or - if appropriate - our nightly PPA <a href="https://launchpad.net/~team-xbmc/+archive/ubuntu/xbmc-nightly">here</a>. If you're on Android, you can <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/org.xbmc.kodi">enrol</a> in our Beta programme and get updates directly from Google Play.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also see changes since Beta 1 <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0b1-Matrix...19.0b2-Matrix">here</a> or browse the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Matrix+19.0-beta+2%22+is%3Aclosed">here</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/pMIDQ3Bf5pA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>So, here we go again. Nothing earth-shattering, just a quick note to tell you that the second Beta of Kodi 19.x "Matrix" is now available…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-beta-2/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Beta 1</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/aZOFWhkdmNc/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 16:41:28 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-beta-1/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 Beta Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 Beta Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/kodi_splash_v19.0_matrix_beta_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>Lights! Camera! Action!</p>
<p>... nearly. It's Beta time for Kodi 19.x "Matrix", so let's take another step towards the Great Unveiling.</p>
<p>As we now move into Beta, this release is much more about fixes than features: while there will be the odd new functionality, we're concentrating very much more on getting everything working properly from this point.</p>
<p>To recap, then, one of the main objectives of 19.x "Matrix" is to release a production version of Kodi with Python 3 addons as early in 2021 as we can. That can only happen with enthusiastic community support, lots of good humour and willingness to see the best in others - well, that and coffee/beer (delete as applicable), of course!</p>
<p>Why Python 3? Simply, because Python 2 went end-of-life in January 2020, so the whole IT industry is lurching over to the new platform. It's generally taking a long time, but it's necessary if you want active support, bugfixes, the latest third-party libraries, security patches, and the like. You can see some of Kodi's announcements about this change <a href="https://kodi.tv/blog?keyword=python&#x26;tag=All">in previous blog posts</a>.</p>
<p>Beyond that, though, here's a quick recap of the major new features in 19.x "Matrix" - as well, of course, as many fixes and code changes that won't be as obvious:</p>
<p><strong>Audio/Music</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improvements covering multi-disc CD sets and box sets; metadata improvements such as better handling of album release dates, album durations, etc.; new fullscreen/visualisation settings; new Matrix-inspired visualisation; support for file tags over http(s).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Music Videos</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improved links with the music library to e.g. fetch related album/artist information, display both videos and albums when searching, display more linked information in info dialogs, etc.; improvements around grouping of all music videos by artist (vs album only); enhanced .nfo handling for multiple performers.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Skin/Look-and-Feel</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Multiple improvements to Estuary, particularly around music and music videos, including: a redesign of the fullscreen/visualisation music window; additional metadata display; new “Now Playing” view; chapter information for music videos; enhanced “now playing” and “next item” views; a generally improved “out of the box” behaviour with regard to music and video library artwork.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Games</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improved game controller support on iOS; improvements to image quality in Pixel Art games.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Playback</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Software decoding of AV1;subtitle improvements with new dark grey colour and selectable opacity; ability to provide a subtitle URI (URL, local file, etc.); static HDR10 and dynamic Dolby Vision HDR support (<em>platform- and client-dependent</em>).</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>PVR</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A host of improvements, including PVR reminders; TV/Radio channel groups, home screen widgets and dynamic PVR categories for Estuary; enhancements to the Group and Channel manager; navigation/usability improvements such as context menus, selection persistence, and EPG controls; info dialog enhancements; improvements to PVR handling via the API.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Security</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Various improvements to user information, e.g. the security implications of enabling external interfaces or a prompt when enabling a broken/deprecated addon; a requirement for a web interface password by default; new origin enforcement for addons and dependencies, so third-party addons can’t overwrite code of other, unrelated addons.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Information Providers/Scrapers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>New Python scrapers for music, TV and movies (linked to the Python 3 move).</li>
</ul>
<p>... plus many code and platform-specific fixes and improvements that might be less visible to most users, but are still significant, such as the move to a single Linux binary for multiple windowing systems (X11, Wayland, and GBM).</p>
<p>After 18 months of hard work by the team and community, we now feel that Kodi v19.x "Matrix" is stable enough to enter beta phase of the release cycle and start to be used "in anger". As above, our focus is now entirely on testing and fixes, moving in steps to a final release as soon as we practically can. This release should be pretty reliable for most users - if you do choose to install it, make sure you know how to roll back, just in case, but you should be safe. We need your help to find and isolate the remaining bugs (including, of course, any regressions), so, please: install, test, and give us clear feedback on any issues you uncover. We can then aim to get these resolved in upcoming releases.</p>
<p>You can get Beta 1 from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/releases/">here</a>. If you're on Android, you can <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/org.xbmc.kodi">enrol</a> in our Beta programme and get updates directly from Google Play.</p>
<p>As usual, you can also see changes since Alpha 3 <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0a3-Matrix...19.0b1-Matrix">here</a> or browse the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Matrix+19.0-beta+1%22+is%3Aclosed">here</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/aZOFWhkdmNc" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Lights! Camera! Action! ... nearly. It's Beta time for Kodi 19.x "Matrix", so let's take another step towards the Great Unveiling. As we now…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-beta-1/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>New Sponsor Announcement: GoatCounter</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/zs9xdDCTE1Q/</link><category>Community</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">yol</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 01:37:47 PST</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/new-sponsor-announcement-goatcounter/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[<p>Last year at FOSDEM, we were approached about our usage of analytics software on our websites that gives visitor data to big companies with servers located in countries with data protection laws that are less strict than what EU citizens are accustomed to. Team Kodi has always had a firm stance against user tracking in our software, so it felt inconsistent that we did not extend the same level of prudence to our websites.</p>
<p> At first, we considered removing analytics altogether. But it quickly became clear that this would be problematic for our Wiki maintainers: Without any insight into what pages are viewed most, it is next to impossible to prioritize the pages to update adequately. We were very happy to come across <a href="https://www.goatcounter.com/">GoatCounter</a>, which solved our problems nicely: It has a strong dedication to privacy and data protection, but still gives us the data we need to maintain the Wiki. Shortly after, we were even happier: It is my pleasure to announce that GoatCounter has joined the ranks of our <a href="https://kodi.tv/sponsors">sponsors</a>!</p>
<p> It is still a very young project, but from our experience it is a great alternative for site owners looking for a privacy-focused hosted analytics solution. Smaller non-commercial sites below 100k pageviews/month enjoy free hosting.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/zs9xdDCTE1Q" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Last year at FOSDEM, we were approached about our usage of analytics software on our websites that gives visitor data to big companies with…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/new-sponsor-announcement-goatcounter/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Alpha 3</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/m_8rlAhf8pQ/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 19:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-3/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Kodi_Splash_v19.0_Matrix_Alpha_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>So... drum roll...hot on the heels of 19.x "Matrix" Alpha 2, and after a quick detour for an unexpected 18.9 "Leia" release, we bring you the stunningly-named 19.x "Matrix" Alpha 3. This will hopefully be the last of our alpha releases, before we move into beta and onto formal release (but no promises, obviously).</p>
<p>Usual caveats: while we're approaching beta, this is still an alpha, and some things will be broken. That is, basically, the whole point of releasing it, after all: find the problems, and fix them before final release.</p>
<p>Here's a non-exhaustive list of the major feature changes since the last release, although there have also been many more improvements and "behind the curtains" fixes:</p>
<p><strong>Music Library</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Small fixes to album duration for music in unusual folder layouts, and triggering rescraping of a single artist or album.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Music Videos</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fetch related album and artist info (including art, bio, review etc) from the music library where appropriate</li>
<li>Display all music videos for an artist, not just the ones related to an album when navigating by artist</li>
<li>Searching from the info dialog for an artist now includes all of related library albums as well as any videos</li>
<li>Possibility to use .nfo files so that the artist list can now show all performers from music videos, not just the main artist</li>
<li>Info dialogs will display data from the music library where there's a corresponding artist and/or album</li>
<li>Fix the <em>same director</em> search for music videos</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Playback</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Correct the colour mapping of HLG HDR playback in SDR mode on Windows 10</li>
<li>Add HLG HDR playback as HDR10 on Windows 10 (as Windows does not support passthrough of HLG)</li>
<li>Added support for more OpenGL bicubic scalers</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Skin/Look-and-Feel</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>[Estuary] Add chapter info from music videos to OSD</li>
<li>[Estuary] Improve the <em>next item in playlist</em> info for music videos by adding artist/album details if available</li>
<li>[Estuary] Improve the <em>Now Playing</em> info for music videos when not in full-screen video by adding artist/album details if available</li>
<li>[Estuary] Optional poster for music videos</li>
<li>Behaviour changes to DialogAddonInfo buttons (e.g. contextual focus defaults to install, update, configure, etc.)</li>
<li>Add PVR.TimeShiftSeekbar infolabel to expose seekbar outside of the SeekBar dialog</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Games</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Implement integer scaling support to improve the viewing quality of Pixel Art games</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Information Providers/Scrapers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>New default Python metadata scrapers for movies and TV shows (replacing old XML scrapers)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>API/JSON-RPC</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Add ability to apply a new subtitle URI to the player, e.g. URL, local file, etc.</li>
<li>Updates to allow VideoLibrary.Clean by directory</li>
<li>Improvements and fixes around PVR handling via the API</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>PVR</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Remember <em>last opened</em> (vs current <em>last played</em>) TV/Radio group across restarts</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Platform-specific</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Linux: move to a single binary for multiple windowing systems (X11, Wayland, and GBM) versus the previous three. Users and package maintainers will no longer have to select a different binary based on the target environment.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you're willing to help find some bugs, you can get Alpha 3 from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/snapshots/">here</a>. Again, though, please: expect some breakage, and don't use this as your daily installation unless you know how to get things working again. If you do make the move and install it, however, please share your experience so we can really get going on those bugs.</p>
<p>As usual, you can see changes since Alpha 2 <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0a2-Matrix...19.0a3-Matrix">here</a>, or browse the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Matrix+19.0-alpha+3%22+is%3Aclosed">here</a>.</p>
<p>Over to you.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/m_8rlAhf8pQ" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>So... drum roll...hot on the heels of 19.x "Matrix" Alpha 2, and after a quick detour for an unexpected 18.9 "Leia" release, we bring you…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-3/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi "Leia" 18.9 Release</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/VLwwY36d9G0/</link><category>Release</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 20:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-189-release/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 18.9 Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 18.9 Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Kodi_Splash_v18.9_Leia_Final_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p><em>Mutter, mutter... "18.8 will be the last", they said... "all efforts will go into 19.x now", they said... famous last words...</em></p>
<p>Okay, one more roll of the "Leia" die, although this one is really driven by circumstances beyond our control. Technical changes by Cloudflare caused significant issues with HTTP access to any site using them - metadata sources, for example - and we need to put in a quick workaround before everyone gets too upset; while 19.x "Matrix" is close, it's not close enough to leave these issues unaddressed. So, as we're building that new code, we thought that we might as well fix a couple of other regressions while we're here.</p>
<p>With no further fanfare, then, here's what you've got in this release:</p>
<ul>
<li>Work around third-party changes to HTTP2 and SSL/encryption that impacted internet access from Kodi by scrapers, streaming addons, etc.</li>
<li>Fix memory leaks in TexturePacker</li>
<li>Fix event server unable to send raw key strikes</li>
<li>Fix issues around directory navigation and incorrectly-set start directories</li>
<li>Fix MediaCodec OES/EGL rendering</li>
</ul>
<p>The full changelog can be found in our GitHub <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/18.8-Leia...18.9-Leia">milestone</a> or you can read the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Leia+18.9%22">here</a>. If you want to read back on the full history of v18 itself, or of previous versions, you can find the corresponding articles in the relevant <a href="https://kodi.tv/tags/release-announcements">blog posts</a>.</p>
<p>Application deployment on different platforms - especially curated "app stores" - varies due to circumstances outside of our control. It may thus take a few more days to appear everywhere, so just hang on until it gets to you.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/VLwwY36d9G0" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Mutter, mutter... "18.8 will be the last", they said... "all efforts will go into 19.x now", they said... famous last words... Okay, one…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-189-release/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Alpha 2</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/0cJonK1ikNA/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 08:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-2/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Kodi_Splash_v19.0_Matrix_Alpha_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>It's been more than a month since our last "preview" release, so it's time we boxed up something new for everyone.</p>
<p>The usual drill applies: this is an alpha, some things will be broken, your home is at risk if something goes wrong, it might run off with your partner, don't blame us if it eats your kittens. Otherwise, though, all should be fine.</p>
<p>Latest changes:</p>
<p><strong>Playback</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Music: Display album duration in info dialog. Album duration can be used in smart playlists in the same way as for songs</li>
<li>Music: Read tags and and album art from music files served from an http(s) server</li>
<li>Music: Fix list view of files containing multiple streams</li>
<li>Feature: Audio decoder addons can now pass more information on Kodi (album, year, notes ...)</li>
<li>Audio decoder addons can now pass more information to Kodi (album, year, notes ...)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Subtitles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>ASS: Fixed timestamp overlapping overlays</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Skin/Look-and-Feel</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Improvements to both music and video library artwork</p>
<ul>
<li>Better "out the box" behaviour, optionally use all image files found in media folders</li>
<li>Artwork levels - max, basic, custom, none</li>
<li>GUI settings for custom configuration of whitelists (replacing awkward editing of advancedsettings.xml)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Redesigned SeekBar that will auto-hide when video playback is paused</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Platform Specifics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Apple TV</p>
<ul>
<li>Fix Kodi crash on start after a manual install with dpkg -i command (jailbroken devices only)</li>
<li>Fix TopShelf feature after a manual install with dpkg -i command (jailbroken devices only except <em>Unc0verTV</em> devices, needs investigation)</li>
<li>Fix missing thumbs on TopShelf items</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Python/Addons</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Fix scripts/plugins not being notified of abortRequest intents on app close</li>
<li>Deprecate xbmc.translatepath in favour of xbmcvfs.translatepath towards convergence with the binary addon API</li>
<li>Broken/deprecated add-ons are now highlighted in the add-on list, and you're now prompted when you try to activate one</li>
<li>Fix: Prevent VFS addon changes (update, disable and uninstall) if in use</li>
<li>Fix: VFS addon problem, where Kodi needed a restart before showing a newly-installed version</li>
<li>Binary addon system revised to ensure higher security in data exchange between addon and Kodi (only inputstream missing)</li>
<li>Revised binary add-on system documentation for outside developers (only inputstream missing)</li>
<li>Internal binary add-on settings dialogs cleaned up, plus updated help text (audioencoder.kodi.builtin.aac, audioencoder.kodi.builtin.wma, screensaver.xbmc.builtin.dim)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you're bold, brave (and possibly a wearing a red shirt), you can get Alpha 2 from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/snapshots/">here</a>. Again, though, please - and adopting a more serious note - expect some breakage, and don't use this as your daily installation unless you know how to get things working again. If you do make the move and install it, however, please do share your experiences back with us so we can really get going on those bugs.</p>
<p>As usual - well, it is open source - you can see what's changed between v18 and this version <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/Leia...19.0a2-Matrix">here</a>, and changes since Alpha 1 <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/19.0a1-Matrix...19.0a2-Matrix">here</a>.</p>
<p>Have fun!</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/0cJonK1ikNA" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>It's been more than a month since our last "preview" release, so it's time we boxed up something new for everyone. The usual drill applies…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-2/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi/Inputstream Adaptive Presentation - 24 September 2020</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/hRJhvpl8V10/</link><category>Conferences</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Team Kodi</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 17:09:22 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodiinputstream-adaptive-presentation-24-september-2020/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Sydney Video Technology Group Logo" alt="Sydney Video Technology Group Logo" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/600_468058366.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>This is just a quick blog post to tell you about a presentation that might be of interest. Glenn Guy (<strong>Aussie Addons</strong>) is giving a presentation on Meetup this Thursday, 24th September, at 18:00 AEST (07:00 UTC) for the Sydney Video Technology group. It's featuring some pretty big names in the Video VOD world.</p>
<p>It came about because the host - Jeremy, the Associate Director of Video Delivery at Optus Sports - made contact on Twitter wondering how the Optus Sport addon was playing back SSAI when their Android app couldn't yet. Matt Huismann (another contributor) explained that Glenn had added X-discontinuity support for live streams into Inputstream Adaptive, and that IA and Kodi was doing all the work. We put him in contact with Glenn - and now Glenn is doing a presentation about it.</p>
<p>He will be mainly talking about Kodi + Inputstream Adaptive + Disney addon (how he added features to IA to accomplish that)</p>
<p>Anyone can join the Meetup to watch:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Sydney-Video-Technology/events/273069747/">https://www.meetup.com/Sydney-Video-Technology/events/273069747/</a></p>
<p>You can also watch on Twitch if they run out of capacity on Meetup:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.twitch.tv/demuxed">https://www.twitch.tv/demuxed</a></p>
<p>Please do join if you're interested.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Edit</strong>: for those who were unable to watch live, here's a link to the Twitch catch-up recording: <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/videos/750423472?t=03h18m18s">https://www.twitch.tv/videos/750423472?t=03h18m18s</a></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/hRJhvpl8V10" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>This is just a quick blog post to tell you about a presentation that might be of interest. Glenn Guy (Aussie Addons) is giving a…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodiinputstream-adaptive-presentation-24-september-2020/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi 19.x "Matrix" - Alpha 1</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/rVid-cE7CfM/</link><category>Prerelease</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 05:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-1/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 19.0 Alpha Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Kodi_Splash_v19.0_Matrix_Alpha_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>So, here we go. Hot on the heels of what is intended to be the <a href="https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-188-release">final release in the 18.x "Leia" series</a>, it's time to give you good people a taste of things to come. So, with no further ado, we'd like to present the first Alpha releases of Kodi 19.x "Matrix".</p>
<p>This is a major release, so, as you'd expect, it comes with many new features. However, it will inevitably cause problems for some people, which is why we'll go through a more traditional Alpha/Beta/Release Candidate model. As such, then, please be aware that installing this will inevitably break things, and we'd really like your help at that point to identify the problems and get them fixed.</p>
<p>So, all that aside... what's actually changed?</p>
<p><strong>Audio/Music</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improved handling of multi-disc CD sets and box sets</li>
<li>Additional metadata tags</li>
<li>Improved handling of album release dates</li>
<li>New setting to open music fullscreen/visualisation window automatically when playback is started</li>
<li>A new, Matrix-inspired music visualisation is now available to install - great care has been put into making this perform well on lower-end systems</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Video</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Software decoding of the AV1 CODEC</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Subtitles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Subtitle opacity can now be changed</li>
<li>New dark grey colour for subtitles</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Estuary Skin</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Redesign of the music fullscreen/visualisation window to match other fullscreen windows - allows fanart and visualisations to be shown without coloured overlays</li>
<li>Additional media info flags added to music fullscreen/visualisation window info display</li>
<li>The default Playlist view now uses the Widelist view format with options on the sideblade menu as in other areas of the skin</li>
<li>A new "Now Playing" view added for music playback, showing media details for both any selected song in the playlist and those for any currently playing song</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Games</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>iOS now supports game controllers (Xbox/PlayStation/other supported Bluetooth controllers)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Platform Specifics</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Darwin (Apple) platforms:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Objective-C code migrated from manual memory management to ARC</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>iOS:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Added showing total/free space</li>
<li>Kodi log can now be shared using native sharing sheet</li>
<li>Kodi GUI is no longer obscured on devices with notch</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>macOS:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Blank Other Displays setting no longer requires app restart</li>
<li>"Toggle fullscreen" now uses default macOS shortcut</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Android</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Static HDR10 support for all source types (if supported by the device)</li>
<li>Dynamic Dolby Vision HDR support for streaming services (if supported by the device)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Windows</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li>Static HDR10 support for all source types (if supported by the GPU)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Information Providers (scrapers)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>New python scrapers for music - available in repo as <strong>Generic Album Scraper</strong> and <strong>Generic Artist Scraper</strong></li>
<li>New python scrapers for TV &#x26; movies - available in repo as <strong>The Movie Database Python</strong> and <strong>The TVDB (new)</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>PVR</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>PVR reminders</li>
<li>TV and radio channel groups and Estuary home screen widgets</li>
<li>Group manager usability enhancements</li>
<li>Channel manager usability enhancements</li>
<li>Guide window navigation controls</li>
<li>Estuary PVR information dialog enhancements</li>
<li>Setting 'Switch to full screen' now supports channel types</li>
<li>Playlist context menu items for recordings</li>
<li>Dynamic PVR categories for Estuary home screen</li>
<li>Ability to sort channels and EPG by the backend order of channels</li>
<li>Support group specific channel numbering and option to start group number locally from 1</li>
<li>Support for starting EPG entries as live</li>
<li>Support displaying recording sizes and being able to sort by them</li>
<li>New, Live, Finale and Premiere for EPG, recordings and timers</li>
<li>Guide window performance improvements</li>
<li>Search window performance improvements</li>
<li>EPG performance and memory usage optimisations</li>
<li>C++ API for PVR Addon development</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Network</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Improved information around the security implications of enabling external interfaces</li>
<li>Added default-on switch to require a password for the web interface</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Addons</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Probably the biggest change: with this release, we move to Python 3 for addons (see note below).</li>
<li>Kodi will now enforce the origin of installed addons and their dependencies. This has been implemented to prevent third party repositories from overwriting code of unrelated add-ons, which was the cause of numerous error reports in the past.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Due to the discontinuation of Python 2, Kodi now utilises Python 3 for addons. Because of this change, this update might disable addons where a compatible version isn't available, although these will be reactivated as soon as their authors provide new versions. The list of Kodi Matrix compatible addons available from the official repository is growing by the week, but not everything has been ported over yet.</em></p>
<p>If you want to take the plunge, you can get Alpha 1 from <a href="https://mirrors.kodi.tv/snapshots/">here</a>. Again, though, please: expect some breakage, don't use this as your daily installation unless you know how to get things working again, and please share your experiences back with us so we can really get going on those bugs.</p>
<p>As usual - well, it is open source - you can see what's changed between v18 and v19 <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/Leia...19.0a1-Matrix">here</a>. It's a long list...</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/rVid-cE7CfM" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>So, here we go. Hot on the heels of what is intended to be the final release in the 18.x "Leia" series, it's time to give you good people a…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-19x-matrix-alpha-1/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi Remote Access Security Recommendations</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/V4s2wrCd928/</link><category>Community</category><category>Deep Dive</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Team Kodi</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-remote-access-security-recommendations/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Password combination lock image by Gino Crescoli from Pixabay." alt="Password combination lock image by Gino Crescoli from Pixabay." src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/password-2781614_1920.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>Kodi includes a powerful web interface that can be used with any browser, but also sits behind the remote control application you use on your phone, or the web front end on your tablet - if you're using Kore, or Chorus, or one of the numerous alternatives, then you're using this interface. However, it has recently been brought to our attention that not all users follow security best practices when enabling this functionality, and are thus exposing themselves to danger. This is partially our fault, since we have not been completely clear about the implications of enabling external interfaces in Kodi. The next Kodi release, 19.x "Matrix", will provide more context when interfaces are enabled, and require a password for the web interface by default. This blog post will detail how you could be affected by an exposed interface at the moment, however, and what to do about it.</p>
<p><strong>Recommendations</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do not use the Kodi web server without setting a reasonably-secure password.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do not expose any Kodi external interface (web server, JSON-RPC, event server ...) directly to the Internet.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do not enable any external interface in Kodi that you don't actually use.</strong> This is especially true for the JSON-RPC service when exposed on all interfaces.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Explanation</strong></p>
<p>The interfaces Kodi provides for external control are, by design, very powerful. It's possible to use the remote control functionality to execute arbitrary code on the box that Kodi runs on, just like you could do this using a traditional IR remote when sitting in front of the TV. In effect, this means that a machine can be completely taken over by an attacker that has access to the web or JSON-RPC interface.</p>
<p>This is why you should <strong>never</strong> run the web server without authentication. It allows anyone with access to the server port to completely control your box. Even if you do not expose the web server to the Internet, other machines including your PC or laptop can do this. This is possible from a standard web browser (via JavaScript), so you might visit a malicious web page that does this in the background and not even realise that it's happening. While the next Kodi version will still allow you to disable the web server password, we strongly recommend to set one. If you already use the web server and do not have a password set, you can do so using the Kodi settings, after which you will also have to configure your remote control application to authenticate using that password.</p>
<p>Also, keep in mind that neither JSON-RPC over TCP nor EventServer (enabled with the "<em>Allow remote control from applications</em>" setting in Kodi) offer any authentication, so they should usually be restricted to access solely from the box on which Kodi is running ("<em>Allow remote control from applications on this system</em>").</p>
<p>We hope this clears some of the confusion and, as always, you can head to the forums if you have any questions.</p>
<p><em>With grateful thanks to Jacob Baines of Tenable, Inc., for highlighting this problem.</em></p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/V4s2wrCd928" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Kodi includes a powerful web interface that can be used with any browser, but also sits behind the remote control application you use on…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-remote-access-security-recommendations/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi "Leia" 18.8 Release</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/a0MuKIqNxU0/</link><category>Release</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 11:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-188-release/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kodi 18.8 Splash Screen" alt="Kodi 18.8 Splash Screen" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Kodi_Splash_v18.8_Leia_Final_1080p.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>So, here we are again. Those of you with eagle eyes may already have seen this rolling out, but just to make everyone else aware - 18.8 is here. In our ongoing quest to make your lives as simple and fulfilling as possible, we're proud to present what is likely to be the final release in the 18.x "Leia" series, before all effort now shifts to 19.x "Matrix".</p>
<p>As usual, this is a bug fix release, so don't go looking for new features. Full details are on <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?page=1&#x26;q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Leia+18.8%22+label%3A%22v18+Leia%22">GitHub</a>, but here's the short form... as you'd expect this late in the 18.x development cycle, this isn't a huge release, but it does include some things we thought were necessary to keep us going until the next major release emerges. In summary, this version:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixes a severe security issue in gnutls</li>
<li>Other significant library/compatibility updates</li>
<li>Gets client/server on MariaDB 10.5.4 working for Android</li>
<li>Fixes video database access for Ubuntu 20.4 and other distros using earlier libfmt versions (search and other filtering failed)</li>
<li>Fixes subtitle handling from archives</li>
<li>Fixes CDDB access</li>
<li>Makes minor improvements to logging and memory reporting/display</li>
<li>Fixes EDLs where skip points are at the very start of a file</li>
<li>Contains code improvements to fix specific events, e.g. race conditions in the EPG or "pause" on end of streams on Android</li>
<li>Enables alpha blending for the video player (Windows)</li>
<li>Better handles specific exceptions (Android, mostly)</li>
</ul>
<p>Thanks to everyone who has helped by reporting, isolating or fixing issues here.</p>
<p>The full changelog can be found in our GitHub <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/compare/18.7-Leia...18.8-Leia">milestone</a> or you can read the merged PRs <a href="https://github.com/xbmc/xbmc/pulls?q=is%3Apr+sort%3Aupdated-desc+milestone%3A%22Leia+18.8%22+label%3A%22v18+Leia%22+">here</a>. If you want to read back on the full history of v18 itself, or of previous versions, you can find the corresponding articles in the relevant <a href="https://kodi.tv/tags/release-announcements">blog posts</a>.</p>
<p>Application deployment on different platforms (notably, Google Play and the Microsoft Store) varies due to circumstances outside of our control. It may thus take a few more days to appear everywhere, so just stay tuned; this is particularly the case in curated stores, where ongoing issues with staffing may mean a further delay before the application is accepted and published. All we can say is to keep looking.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/a0MuKIqNxU0" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>So, here we are again. Those of you with eagle eyes may already have seen this rolling out, but just to make everyone else aware - 18.8 is…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-188-release/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>New Kore version - v2.5.1</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/HD9ocWogi5I/</link><category>Release</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Team Kodi</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 14:00:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/new-kore-version-v251/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Kore logo" alt="Kore logo" src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/84595474-00aa5100-ae50-11ea-86ab-cc7b4a47b977.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p><strong>Kore v2.5.1 Released!</strong></p>
<p>Team Kodi are proud to announce the release of the latest version of our Kore Android remote. This version is mostly a bug fix release, but it also includes some improvements that we hope you like.</p>
<p>The most relevant changes for this version are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Add support for sharing from Amazon Prime Videos and from Arte (The European Culture Channel) to Kodi</li>
<li>Allow local playback of items in the "Files" section</li>
<li>Fix download of media files not working</li>
<li>Fix "Play from here" in the "Files" section</li>
<li>Prevent continuous refresh of playlist in the remote section in some configurations</li>
<li>Support sharing of local filenames with spaces in the name</li>
<li>Support for self-signed certificates</li>
<li>Remember last used tab in various sections</li>
</ul>
<p>Kore is available now from the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.xbmc.kore&#x26;hl=en">Google Play Store</a> and from <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/org.xbmc.kore/">F-Droid</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/HD9ocWogi5I" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>Kore v2.5.1 Released! Team Kodi are proud to announce the release of the latest version of our Kore Android remote. This version is mostly a…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/new-kore-version-v251/</feedburner:origLink></item><item><title>Kodi "Leia" 18.7 on Android</title><link>http://feeds.kodi.tv/~r/xbmc/~3/aLX5gtj3sD8/</link><category>Community</category><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Prof Yaffle</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:30:00 PDT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-187-android/</guid><content:encoded xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><![CDATA[
                    <figure>
                      <img title="Android robot: the Android robot is reproduced or modified from work created and shared by Google and used according to terms described in the Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution License." alt="Android robot: the Android robot is reproduced or modified from work created and shared by Google and used according to terms described in the Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution License." src="https://kodi.tv/images/blog/Android_Robot.webp" />
                    </figure>
                  <p>When we launched 18.7 across all platforms a couple of weeks ago, it became apparent that there were some problems on Android that wouldn't wait until a future point release to be fixed. These issues - regressions, specifically around micro-stutter and discontinuities on multi-chapter streams - came about because we'd re-introduced MediaCodec JNI over MediaCodec NDK to address scaling/aspect ratio issues that people were seeing on AFTV devices.</p>
<p>As such, we immediately paused deployment through Google Play while we sorted things out. We fixed those in an 18.7.1 interim release, which we rolled out through the Android Play beta channel. However, this immediately revealed new problems: automatic feedback showed program exceptions when playing DRM-protected streams on incapable devices (due to the devices' DRM security level).</p>
<p>To avoid segfaults, and thus Kodi termination, we again halted the beta rollout, and went back to work. We've now updated the code to handle exceptions identically to the previous NDK, but we've also fixed the aspect ratio issues we were seeing on AFTV - hopefully, the best of both worlds.</p>
<p>So, with that done, we can start the roll-out once more with a new version of Kodi 18.7 just for Android (internally marked as 18.7.200). This will initially be rolled out on the Play store beta channel, and then - assuming no other glitches trip us up - it will then become the official, final "mass market" 18.7 for Android. It has no impact on other platforms.</p>
<p>The beta APK is rolling out now, so should be pushed to registered beta testers. All going well, we'll then release it to a broader audience in due course with a general Play update, and it will, of course, also be available for download directly from the Kodi website.</p>
<p>If you're interested in helping us to make the best media centre software there is, you can sign up to the beta programme <a href="https://play.google.com/apps/testing/org.xbmc.kodi/">here</a>.</p><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/xbmc/~4/aLX5gtj3sD8" height="1" width="1" alt=""/>]]></content:encoded><description>When we launched 18.7 across all platforms a couple of weeks ago, it became apparent that there were some problems on Android that wouldn't…</description><feedburner:origLink>https://kodi.tv/article/kodi-leia-187-android/</feedburner:origLink></item></channel></rss>
